Doesn't the training mention that
those tier threes are useless?
You only wanna focus on quality paid links.
Those citations are not citations that you buy off. Fiverr.
Those are citations that we've manually prospected for.
So for us it's gonna be things like avo, FindLaw, yelp,
justia expertise.com.
Those are like actual websites
that people use to find lawyers.
Those are on our list.
Those are really important for, I mean,
for a lot of reasons, right?
I don't quite like, they're,
they're not quite like contextual links,
but they're an important part of the
process, if that makes sense.
Do that in month one. We knock them
out, we have a VA build them.
And uh, you know, after that, then our sole focus is on
contextual links after that.
Like po, I don't wanna call 'em pr, but like SEO O links.
Do you find that many times clients want
to alter the content and selling AI content isn't
as attractive as having some real copywriter that
we came across that recently until I showed somebody like,
like it's just about the output.
If you tell them like, yeah, we're automating content
with ai, of course they're gonna be like, well,
I'm not gonna pay you, or, that sounds cheap.
Or like, doesn't Google not like that?
You just gotta be able to communicate it to 'em, man.
So like, if you want to tell them
that you're using a human writer
that's on you, you can tell them that.
I don't personally, I tell 'em that we use AI
and we've got a really good process
for it, and I just show 'em the content.
They're like, okay, this is good.
So, and cl clients never wanna alter it.
I mean, for, for farmers, I know we don't, like,
I would say like maybe 10%
of our clients are, are the stick in the mud.
And you guys get the cost of those lawyer citations?
Yes, we do. So if it's a onetime fee
on a platform, we'll pay it.
If it's a monthly recurring fee like BBB is on our list,
then we will ensure that they,
we use their card to set it up.
And if they don't want do it, then that's fine,
but we will eat the cost
of the other ones if it's a one-time payment.
And again, I think it's important, it's a good question
because I think it's important to understand how
to budget those costs out.
Because if you're like, okay, for us to get
through all these tier three citations,
it's gonna cost us 1200 bucks.
We might wanna split that over two months, right?
Or like do five, 10 citations a month over the course
of the, you know, so you can spread them out
and allocate them in a way
that adheres better to your budget.
I'm working with an attorney in la technically we can target
hundreds of area and practice area pages,
but is there a point where it's too much?
Yeah, absolutely. You should really
only be doing it for what?
For the places where they have verified locations,
but they don't have a verified location in
those places that we don't do it.
Meaning a verified Google business profile with an office.
It's, that's a doorway page strategy.
It's an old school really spammy tactic.
I know some agencies still do it,
but like, it's, it's pretty spammy to do that.
I wouldn't do that. So, yeah.
Now within LA for example, like LA you might do, like,
they have like pockets
of la like if they have an office in downtown la,
you could do practice area pages for like,
like the Hills West Hollywood, stuff like that.
But I wouldn't go outside of the LA area for it personally.
It gets very spammy. What's your dropout rate rate
of each stage of your sales process?
So, okay, it's a good question.
So I would say, let's just use like a number.
Let's say we get 10 leads. 10 leads in, right?
I will usually cancel three of those leads
and not even do a discovery call with them.
Maybe more three to four, three to four of those leads.
We'll say 30% drops off.
They don't get to a discovery call
because I look at their website
and I'm like, they're too small.
It's a new website. They have no Instagram profile.
I'm not like, I'm not taking a discovery call
with somebody who's really has, it's not just,
not even remotely in the atmosphere of
what I know it is gonna qualify them as a lead.
So 30% before even the discovery call, discovery call
to proposal is actually pretty high.
I would say like we, only 10%
of the time we don't do a proposal, right?
Because if I, I'm like heavily qualifying the people,
it might be 30 to 40% don't make it to a discovery call.
Like basically if they make it to a discovery call,
I have a really good sense of if,
if they're gonna make it to the proposal or not.
And then from there, I would say it's about a 50%.
I, no, I would say like 30 to 60% close rate.
I know that's a very big, like wide gap,
but it depends on if it's SEO has a very low,
SEO would be closer to 30% Facebook ads
and PPC is closer to 60%.
Facebook closes very well because they know what exactly
what they're getting from it.
They know exactly what the cost per case is.
They have a lot more control over it.
It's more expensive, but it just has a better close rate.
And that, again, that 30 to 60% also
because a lot of people will come back over a long period
of time and say, Hey, I'm ready now.
So after, you know, I I, I pitched them, you know,
six months later they come back
and they're like, Hey, you know,
like we got our ducks in order.
You know, that happens quite a bit.
So that's what our, if you picture like a, you know,
percentage rate, so like 30, 30, 40% make it
to discovery 90%, then make it to from there, make it
to proposal and then 30 to 60 end up becoming cleanse.
Those are, those are about our numbers.
What are you upselling process?
Do run them through the same client.
We don't have any upsells. I'm pitching, I'm pitching
what I'm pitching, I'm pitching the upsell.
You know, like you're, you are getting
what I believe is best for you.
We don't have any upsells. We don't have a single upsell.
I mean, technically we could do like add-on PPC
or Facebook later on, but I am pitching them
what I think is best for them at that time.
There is no upsell, if that makes sense.
What is one thing you usually drop from scope when
they say it's too expensive?
I don't, I don't usually drop too much stuff. Man.
Again, like I, like, I'm very clear with them.
Like I, this is not a negotiation table.
Like this isn't like I'm pitching you 10 for you
to come back and be like, well we could do six
because I already asked you if this nu like
I, they're getting that number.
It is not coming outta nowhere. They're very aware
that they're getting a, a, a, a quote
of $10,000 since the discovery call.
I tell them on the discovery call,
'cause I know the ballpark, I'll tell them, Hey, for,
you know, a personal injury firm in Miami,
you're looking at like eight to $12,000 a month.
Is that, ooh, is that something that you could do?
And they, and if they say yes,
then like that's what to expect.
Like, I don't chip, I, I don't like
to chip stuff away from the proposal
because I'm just taking away the results.
So I tell 'em that if
they're like, yeah, can we reduce this?
I'm like, well if you, are you willing
to wait longer to get results?
And they're gonna be like, no. They'll be like, well this is
what it's, you know, like, I'm sorry man, I can't, you know,
if like you gave me a a an expectation of results, this is
what it's gonna cost for us to do that.
You know, now there's are sometimes Adrian
where I'll be like, okay, like we can do less links
or less content, but it, it's nominal, right?
Like, so like that 10,001 that I showed you,
we could drop it down to like, like, okay,
well if we do 10,000 words a month, I can take $2,000 off.
You know? But even that, Adrian too, it's like I still,
we're still gonna end up doing the same amount of content
because like, I'm not gonna shortchange them
because they're gonna fire us if they don't get results.
So like, you know, it's basically them saying
like, this is too much.
It's more like, okay, well what are you willing to pay?
Like if you can gimme a number that you're willing to pay,
then maybe I can, I can work something here.
But we usually don't end up dropping off too much
because like, I, I'm quoting this based on
what I believe is I need,
it's what they need to get results.
So I don't like to chop it down
because then it's like, well I'm only hurting ourselves too,
because ultimately we're gonna keep
getting paid if they're getting results.
And like this is the scope to get them results.
So, but again, Adrian, if, if you're in that situation,
the two areas where you can chop down are always content
links because those are the variable costs, right?
Not like you can be like, all right, well we'll only do half
the technical SEO audit, you know, like it is what it is.
But there's definitely, there's definitely pockets you can
tap into for that.
Daniel said in your sales process,
have you noticed an aha moment at any particular stage
or any comment these on
what really resonates with attorneys?
Yeah, they only care about money.
They only want, they only care
about leads and signed clients.
They don't care about leads. They
just care about care about signed cases.
That's it. All they care about.
That's why Facebook works so well
because I can tell 'em exactly
what they're gonna pay per, per case.
And that's why they sign on the dotted line on one call.
So yeah, that's all they care about.
They don't care about traffic, they don't care about queue
rankings, they don't care about meetings,
they don't care about none of that.
They just wanna make money. That's,
that's all they care about.
That's all I care about too. That's why we do so well,
how would you respond to a client who says like,
what do you do after month six?
Doesn't, this hap doesn't happen often,
but it catches me off guard.
Do you guys redo audits and reoptimize the website
or just continue with the recurring deliverables?
I just, we, yeah, so like we, we will get asked that, right?
And what, what I tell them too is that's why, you know,
we go month to month is that, you know, I'll tell them
that like, look, once we're the first, the first couple
of months are definitely pretty labor intensive
with like audits and strategy.
But you know, where you're really gonna start seeing
results is in month three.
And that's because what we're doing is we're
just building, building, building.
So I'm tell, I tell 'em that we're just always
in building mode after that.
And I tell them too, like, that's where you want to be.
You want to be in building mode.
You don't want us to be in audit mode
because audits don't move the needle audits are just taking
time away from the work that needs to be done,
which is building assets and promoting assets.
So that's all I tell Andres, you know, a lot of times too,
those are people that are just kind
of a little bit picky about, I wanna make sure
that you're doing the work that I'm paying you for.
You know, but like, that's why we don't quote on hours.
'cause those are the type of people that are like in month
six will be like, Hey, send me your hours report.
And it's like, I haven't done anything for you this month.
So, you know, that's why getting off of hours
and not presenting hours is also important
because those people nitpick on them.
On my question for upselling, what kind of,
what you're talking about from Adrian's question.
Some clients don't want everything right away.
In my experience, will SEO like is SEO, right?
There's nothing else. Like, dropping stuff out
of SEO will not make it SEO if that makes sense.
You know, and also too, guys,
like it's very important you understand
that these people don't know what they want.
You are the expert. They're not telling you, like,
I'm not walking into a dentist
and being like, Hey, like you need
to do this cranial on my molar.
Or like, I'm not walking into my lawyer's office
who I'm paying a lot of money and being like
telling them how to do their job.
Like that's almost a sign of disrespect when they do that.
So if they're like, if that's how they do it, then I'm like,
you came to the wrong place buddy.
Like I, I exist to make you money.
I quoted you based on the conversations that we had
that you gave me buy-in on, right?
Like, you, you got there.
There needs to be a little bit of like, kind of like, hmm.
Like no, like you came to me here.
Like, don't, like you're not gonna nit take
and tell me what you want.
Like, you want, you want clients.
This is the proposal on pitch to get you clients.
We can't chip things away from this.
You like, that's not the way that this works.
SEO especially is an ecosystem.
It's like we can't just like kick away one
of the table this, the, the,
the legs on the table inspect it to stand, you know,
like they don't want everything right
away because they're cheap.
And I don't mean that in like a disrespectful way.
They just don't wanna pay for it. But like,
it is what it is, man.
Like it, uh, like it is your job to be the expert,
the consultant, and to walk them through it to make sure
that they really understand that.
Like, like, yeah,
again, like putting it back in their shoes.
Like if you're working with dentist and like, like,
all right, I'm gonna come in to get my my molar filled,
but like only fill half of it.
'cause I only want to pay this. They're gonna be like,
go f yourself, dude.
You know what I mean? So like there, there's a,
and there's a, there's a way,
I'm obviously being very arrogant about this,
but there's a way to communicate this in a way that
positions you as the authority as an expert.
You know, it's being very comparable, collected.
And if they're like, so if you give an example Skylar,
I can maybe give you a rebuttal on how I would deal with it.
Like what is, like what is a, what is, what is an example
of a client not wanting everything
right away in your experience?
So I can kind of tell you how I would handle it.
Because, you know, when that happens for me, I,
it doesn't really happen to us that much.
I basically would just get a no.
Like people really won't be like, oh, this is too much
because oh, I'll tell 'em, I'll snap at 'em
and be like, yo, like I told you, this is
what it was gonna cost two times
before you took three hours of my time
and four hours of my team's time to put this all together.
Like you knew what it was gonna cost.
Like we, you looked me in the eye on a Zoom call
and I told you and you said yes, that's fine.
So like, you know, they usually, we don't, we,
I don't get a lot of the, oh, like
can we reduce the pricing on this?
I mean sometimes maybe like 10%
of the time, but I'm just like, no.
Like no, I can all do the same thing.
I'll be like, do you give up?
Do you give discounts on your retainer? And they say no.
And I'm like, okay.
You know, and I'm like, if you wanna find a cheap ratio,
that's up to you, but you're gonna get what you pay for.
You're gonna be back here in three months having been burned
again by another agency
who over promise and under delivered.
Because I walked you through what like,
and this is an important part too, right, is, is
to make sure that they understand why
things cost what they cost.
That's a very important part of the process that I do
with them through the proposal process,
through the analysis process.
The analysis is very good for that
because when I'm showing them content deficiencies,
I'm like, you wonder why you're not getting results?
Because like you only have a third of the content
that your competitors do.
Content ain't free. You know what it's gonna take
to write 40, 40 practice area pages,
you know, like that costs money.
Like real money that costs a lot of money.
You know, like that costs money.
The links cost money, the, like the, the time
and effort costs, money, all that stuff costs money.
So, you know, I think it's important that like you really,
it what it sounds like is in some of these markets,
like dentists maybe where they're aware market
because they know that they need it,
but they don't really know what they're
looking at, which is understandable.
I wouldn't know what I'm looking at if I'm looking at teeth.
I didn't, I'm not a dentist, you know,
but you know, you just need to make sure
that you're explaining it to 'em, walking them through it,
really just holding their hand through it so
that they understand what they're looking
at and what they're paying for.
You know, it's important that you break down the cost.
A lot of agencies don't,
and the people are like, why am I paying 10 grand?
Like, I don't even know what's happening. Do you think a per
result model, AKA $200 per accident case might re resonate
and have a higher close rate
with attorneys at a monthly flat retainer?
So obviously that's what they want.
But like, I'm gonna say no, like one, you have
to be extremely good at getting them at that cost
and like it's gonna be variable.
And when you don't deliver on that cost, they're not gonna,
they're, they're, they're not to be messed with.
So yeah, I mean if you can, if you know
what your cost per case is, which like we do, we know
what our cost per case is on Facebook,
that's about $3,000, $4,000.
We tell them what the expected cost per
case is, which definitely helps.
But I don't contract under that.
Like you don't want to do a per result model,
especially with attorneys.
'cause you also have to front the cost for that.
Like are you willing to pay the ad costs upfront
because then they're paying, they're only paying you
for the outcome of it, which is your, the ad cost plus you.
So like, it's a very difficult model to make work.
It's extremely expensive. One of our media buyers
who was working for us for a while left
to do his only generation model
and I just, I just caught up in the last week.
He said he burned a half a million dollars
before he was able
to get his model profitable on selling leads.
So it's a very, very, very expensive thing to do.
Obviously they jump at it, you sell more of it,
but like to hit that number consistently
and then you also have to deal
with like, oh, Facebook changed.
They, they dropped the Andromeda.
Or like, cost per clicks keep going up.
You know what I'm saying? There's more advi It's a very
difficult model in SEO especially.
Like you can't, you can't know what that cost is.
You just can't. So it's, it's kind
of irresponsible to do for SEO.
It has to be a paid traffic model,
but they'll, they'll buy it for sure.
It's easier to sell. So I guess
your question, is it easier to sell?
Yeah, it'll have a higher close rate for sure,
but like, you're gonna have hell of a time delivering on it.
And for SEO that's impossible to, to pitch.
And it's, again, it's why it's irresponsible as well.
Tyler said, I think you explained it well.
It sounds like my sales process just needs work.
I've had some where they wanna reduce scope
to get a certain price, less links, less content, et cetera.
That can happen. It definitely can happen.
You know, again, and this is also why working
with the same type of prospect over
and over again is so powerful
because it does give you like, it, it,
it increases your margin quite a bit
because for us with links, it's like,
okay, they want less links, it's fine.
We're just ordering less links
basically, you know, for content.
You know, if, if, if they were
to push back on that, like it's fine.
We're not really losing a ton of profit
by selling less, if that makes sense.
What happens when a law firm
or client adds additional locations
while you're working with them?
Do you add an addendum and quote one new locations?
Or you use the same budget?
We usually just use the same budget.
So like, it, it, it depends, right?
If they were to add like 10 locations, then we add, but
If it's one location, it's just copy and pasting the work.
It's, it's really not that much work.
So we'll quote them based on the number of locations
that they have in the beginning,
but we usually don't go through that part.
'cause it's usually like after a couple months
and it's like the work has already kind of died down.
It's like, we'll just do it for 'em.
It's not really we'll just you allocate the content
and the links to that new location, you know,
and it takes, you know, it could take two, three months
to build out the pages sometimes,
depending on their, their scope.
But you definitely can quote more for it.
We've tried, we've done that before in the past,
but like, it just slows things down
and then they're like, I don't really wanna do it.
And then if when they don't do it, then it's like, oh,
we're like not as invested in SEO.
Like it's a good sign if they're adding more locations
because it means that it's working, you know,
and they're seeing value in it and they want more of it.
So I wouldn't, uh, it's up to you though, you know, like, I,
I don't think there's a, a right or wrong way to do that.
That's really purely like
what your client management style is.
Jake asked on the q
and a section, I just saw this here, he said, hi, I'm Jake,
how do you convince clients that CTR manipulation is safe?
We provide white label CTR service for high CCPC clients.
I would never tell a client that I'm doing that,
Jake personally, I have no issue with it.
I'm a dirty SEO myself.
But like, I would never tell a client that we're doing that.
It is very black hat, it's very manipulative.
I'm not saying that it doesn't work.
We've tested it and it didn't really work for our clients.
But I wouldn't tell a client,
I would say especially an attorney
dude, like, you don't wanna do that.
Like, the issue with CTR manipulation two is that one,
if you have data to show otherwise, so you wanna do it
for me and prove me wrong, I'm happy to let you do that.
But like we've tested multiple vendors,
we tested like Uber drivers
that were like doing it from their phones.
It didn't work, it didn't do anything.
And the other issue then, just that it really,
it really skews the data.
You know, like we report on GBP clicks, impressions, calls,
and like when you're messing with that data,
it really skews the client's data
and then creates other problems.
The client's like, oh, we saw a spike in clicks this month,
but not phone calls or leads or cases.
So like I'm just a fan personally
of doing things a little bit more by the book, I guess.
And again, I'm not, this is not like a
place of judgment by any means.
It's just like a, we'll do whatever it takes to get it
to work, but like the, for us, like the,
the risk wasn't worth the reward
and I would not tell clients
that you're doing it directly, man.
Like, it, it is not a, it's not something I would tell them
that you're doing personally.
You know, that is better, Jake, that you work
through agencies than, or, I mean if clients buy
and do it directly, that's fine, but like,
I wouldn't tell clients that you're doing it personally.
Just take the, if it's working for, you're getting
and it's working on rankings, great.
Just take the ranking as the, as the, as the proof
of the pudding for meta Ads services.
How did you decide on your minimum flat rate?
That's a good question. So it started at 5,000,
now we're down to 4,000.
I started at 5,000
because I was like, this is costing me a lot
because we didn't have a lot of clients
and it was a lot of work between creative
and video editing and all that stuff.
And I had to get to a flat fee pricing.
'cause that's how they wanted to, that's, that's
how they really thought about it.
But, you know, it, it was kind of like a, a bit of a,
a dartboard too, just like understanding
what the market's charging for, you know,
and we were definitely overpriced. We
Dropped, dropped to 4,000 because we were just getting a
lot of pushback on the pricing.
So 4,000 has been our sweet spot for personal injury,
but we'll go as low as 3000
for like business lawyers and stuff like that.
And it still works because once you have the process done,
that's a big thing is like, once you have the process done,
the more clients you have, the cheaper it gets.
If that makes sense, right?
Like, but the first couple clients, it's expensive to hell
because you have, you know, you're building the team
and you know, but once you get over like 10, 15 clients,
then it becomes economies of scale when it comes
to leveraging those people.
And the more clients you have,
the cheaper those people costs.